Preliminary Guide to the E. Byrne Hackett Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
E. Byrne Hackett papers
1905-1954
MS 1602
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, speeches, and memorabilia documenting E. Byrne Hackett's career in publishing and bookselling.
Hackett, Edmond Byrne, 1879-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Edmond Byrne Hackett was born in Kilkenny, Ireland on June 8, 1879 and came to the United States in 1895. He was employed as a salesman by Doubleday Page & Company in New York from 1901-1907, and as manager of publishing by Baker & Taylor Company from 1907-1909. Hackett served as director of the Yale University Press soon after its founding in 1908. He was also the founder of the Brick Row Book Shop in New York. Hackett died on November 10, 1953.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, speeches, and memorabilia documenting E. Byrne Hackett's career in publishing and bookselling.
Publishers and publishing -- United States; Hackett, Edmond Byrne, 1879-; Yale University Press
- Inventory, 1905-1954
  - Correspondence
    - A-L, 1910, 1913, 1915, 1921, 1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bigelow, John, 1909-1912, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brick Row Brook Shop, Inc., 1926, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1915 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Day, George Parmly, 1910-1912, 1915-1916, 1926, 1928, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Goldsmith, Alfred F., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Goodyear, William H., 1911-1912, 1914-1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hackett, Kathleen, 1906-1907, 1912, 1921, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hackett, Madge (wife), 1905, 1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - M-Z, 1907, 1909, 1913-1914, 1917, 1925, 1928, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Porter, Arthur Kingley, 1909-1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Quinn John, 1905-1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 12 - 13)
    - Quinn, John: correspondence pertaining to the publishing of a story by James Joyce in The Egoist, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The White House, 1911 November (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Subject files
    - Collecting of books, notes pertaining to, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Printing of books, notes pertaining to, 1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Elizabethan Club: bookplate and facsimile of Elihu Yale's signature to letter in the possession of the Elizabethan Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Yale University Press: finances, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Yale University Press: manufacturing schedule, 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Unidentified, 1905, 1954, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Writings and Speeches
    - Speech to the Knights of St. Patrick, by [E. Byrne Hackett], n.y. March 17 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "A Voice From the World," by Mary L. Hackett, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "Mephistopheleia," by Arthur Kingsley Porter, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Biographical information, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Loose papers and notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Memorabilia, 1915, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1911, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)